

LUIS PALACIOS



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced professional bringing successful 18 years of career in data analysis roles within large and fast-paced corporations. Release-planning specialist trained in advanced BI development, Oracle Hyperion Planning and MS Excel modelling. Creative solutions architect with real-time problem-solving flexibility. Proven ability to learn quickly and adapt to new situations.

SKILLS

- Business Intelligence: QlikView, QlikSense, Tableau, PowerBl
- Reporting: P&L, Cash flow, CAPEX, Balance, operational databases
- Financial tools: Oracle Hyperion Planning, HFM, Smartview
- MS Office: High Proficiency (especially Excel including advanced formulas, Pivot tables, Macros, charts)
- Corporate: +12 years experience in large corporation institutions
- OS: MS Windows desktop and Server, Mac OSX, Linux
- Data analysis: Python, R, SQL

WORK HISTORY

Rivera Maintenance & Building | Windsor, On

Feb 2022 to Current

Cleaning Team Member

Self-employed | Santiago, Chile **Financial and BI Consultant**

Apr 2021 to Nov 2021

- Maintain and Configure BI Server
- Update BI financial dashboards.
- Responded to specific BI requests from financial team personnel, creating data packets with requested information in easily understandable formats.

Laureate Education Inc. | Santiago, Chile **Management Control Engineer**

Nov 2009 to Mar 2021

- Coordinate and lead activities related to the validation, mapping, cleansing, and conversion of financial data (P&L, Cash flows, Balance, CAPEX, operational data)
- Implemented an automatized process through QlikView and Hyperion, improving time reporting from 6 hours to 30 minutes.
- I trained financial teams in reporting in the best accurate way.
- Maintained and adjust reporting packages to senior management and operational reports to Hyperion Planning
- Gained extensive knowledge in data entry, analysis, and reporting.
- Responsible for daily enrollment reports to senior management
- Develop Business Intelligence (BI) solutions for the Financial, Marketing, Sales, and Legal department.
- Worked effectively in fast-paced environments.

DTS Chile. | Santiago, Chile **Process Analyst and Quality**

Apr 2003 to Nov 2009

• Analyzed process flows and identified areas of improvement to increase productivity and reduce costs.

- Gathered documentation and created reports on asserted information.
- HP & Compaq customer service and technical support (call canter agent)

EDUCATION

St. Clair College

Data Analytics for Business, Diploma

Windsor, Ontario. Canada

UEM Spain – UNAB Chile Jul 2020

Apr 2023

Mar 2023

MBA, Master Business Administration

Madrid, Spain – Santiago, Chile

Universidad Nacional Andrés Bello (UNAB)

Jul 2013

Bachelor Business Administration

Santiago, Chile

Universidad Diego Portales (UDP) Dec 2004

Computer and Information Systems Management

Santiago, Chile

AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS

Rivera Maintenance & Building
Employee recognition

Conferred for highlighted work performance.

Laureate Education Inc. Dec 2006

Global recognition Collaboration Award

Global recognition conferred among all network financial teams. This Award was given for my contributions and share all my findings with my colleagues and other regional teams.

LINKEDIN https://www.linkedin.com/in/lmpalacios/

REFERENCES References available upon request.